William Francis Gray Swann Papers 1903-1962 Mss.B.Sw1
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Articles and lectures, 14.5 Linear feet
  - Miscellaneous items on physics (Box 65)
  - Miscellaneous lecture notes (Box 65)
  - Miscellaneous speeches (Box 65)
  - Miscellany (Box 65)
  - Molecular theory of magnetism (Box 66)
  - Momentum equation (Box 66)
  - Moore School exams, with Dr. Swann's notes (Box 66)
  - Moore School talk, Oct. 24, 1941 (Box 66)
  - Motion in the celestial domain (Temple University), Oct. 22, 1961 (Box 66)
  - Motion of particles between poles of magnet (Box 66)
  - Moving lines of magnetic force (Box 66)
  - Multiple values of spec. ionization produced by cosmic ray entities (Box 66)
  - Music as a hobby, December 22, 1942 (Box 66)
    Radio talk at Schenectady
  - Music, Perception, and the Physical World, March 10, 1954 (Box 66)
    Foundation for integrated education, Ethical culture auditorium
  - Music, Teaching... and future, Jan. 29, 1953 (Box 66)
    Sent to Naylor, Cincinnati Conservatory of Music
  - Music, the instrument and the player, Oct. 25, 1938 (Box 66)
    Women's Faculty Club, University of Pennsylvania
  - Musical acoustics (Box 66)
  - Musical elements, Strengths of (unfinished) (Box 66)
  - Musical therapy, Jan. 15, 1945 (Box 66)
  - National outlook in science (Box 66)
  - National Research Council. American Geophysical Union (Box 66)
  - Nature of cosmic ray phenomena at high altitudes (Box 66)
  - Nature of cosmic rays, 2 folders (Box 66)
    Published in Sky and Telescope, see Federer
  - Nature of field in magnetized iron (unfinished) (Box 66)
  - Nature of primary particles responsible for cosmic ray phenomena (Box 66)
  - Nature of research in physics (Box 66)
  - Nature of scientific thought (Temple University), April 11, 1961 (Box 66)
  - Necessity for the motion of the positive electricity in the atom (Box 66)
  - Neutron and gamma ray scattering (Box 66)
  - Neutron capture, Van de Graaff group (Box 66)
  - Neutron scattering work at Bartol (Box 66)
  - Neutron, background in, scattering experiment (Box 66)
  - New demands upon the individual in relation to science (Box 66)
  - New demands upon the individual in relation to science, March 4, 1938 (Box 66)
    New York Adult Education Council
  - New era in science (Box 66)
  - New era in sciences, March 27, 1959 (Box 67)
    Mineralogical society of Pennsylvania, Schwenksville, Pa.
  - New problems in cosmic rays, October 5, 1948 (Box 67)
    New York Academy of Science
  - New quantum dynamics (Box 67)
  - New quantum physics (Box 67)
  - New type of electroscope (Box 67)
  - Newspaper interviews (Box 67)
  - Newton, Isaac, 2 folders (Box 67)
  - Noble musical heritage (Box 67)
  - Noble musical heritage, June 4, 1945 (Box 67)
    Philadelphia Musical Academy, Commencement address
  - Non-Euclidean space (Box 67)
  - Non-unidirectional emission of Hoffman Stoesse (Box 67)
  - Note on electrical conductivity of metals under alternating frequencies (Box 67)
  - Note on the dissipative forces (Box 67)
  - Notes, 2 folders (Box 67)
  - Notes for round table broadcast, Washington, December 12, 1936 (Box 67)
  - Notes on energy of entry to atmosphere (Box 67)
  - Notes on ionization by high energy particles (unfinished) (Box 67)
  - Notes on Lecture #1, Experiments, January 5, 1951 (Box 67)
  - Notes on linear accelerator (Box 67)
  - Notes on particles through magnetic fields (unfinished) (Box 67)
  - Nuclear phenomena in relation to cosmic rays (unfinished), Dec. 18, 1942 (Box 67)
    Chemical Society Baltimore
  - Nuclear physics (Box 67)
  - Nucleons, Certain matters pertaining to internal structure (Box 67)
  - Numerically consistent corpuscular theory of cosmic rays, 2 folders (Box 68)
  - Of what use is science (Box 68)
  - Of what use is science?, December 2, 1935 (Box 68)
    Radio address from Franklin Institute
  - Ogilvie, Douglas C. World War III (Box 68)
  - On H. Alfven's theory of magnetic storms on cosmic ray intensity (Box 68)
  - On science (Box 68)
  - On sub-space and allied matters (Box 68)
  - On the calculation of steady state temperature distributions (Box 68)
  - On the origin of the earth's electric charge (Box 68)
  - On the significance of the results in experiments on the variation of residual ionization with pressure (Box 68)
  - On the statistical and thermodynamical relations of radiant energy (Box 68)
  - On the teacher of physics (Box 68)
  - Orbit of particles in field (Box 68)
  - Origin of the earth's electric and magnetic phenomena (Box 68)
  - Oscillations of a sphere in a wave train (Box 68)
  - Outline for a speech (Box 68)
  - Output voltage of a piezoelectric crystal as a function of time (Box 68)
  - Overall efficiency of thermocouples etc (Box 68)
  - Paganini and Fourier series (Box 68)
  - Particle accelerators Memorandum (Box 68)
  - Penetrating radiations (Box 68)
  - Permeability, Measurement of (Box 68)
  - Petition by students in electron theory II (Box 68)
  - Phase angle between current and voltage, etc (Box 68)
  - Phenomena associated with cosmic rays (Box 68)
  - Philadelphia Record (Box 68)
    - Are death rays possible? 2nd article (Box 68)
    - Atomic particles of physics and what they do. 3rd article (Box 68)
    - Can restriction on research hold the atom bomb a secret? (Alchemist) (Box 68)
    - Is there a defense against atomic bombs? (Box 68)
    - Letter to ----, Sept. 12, 1945 (Box 68)
    - Physicist explains ABC of A-bomb: Nature's secret finally discovered (Box 68)
    - Waves and what they do published, Sept. 23, 1945 (Box 68)
    - What can a pound of U-235 do? 1st article (Box 68)
  - Philosophical aspects in modern physics (Box 68)
  - Philosophical concepts in physics (Box 68)
  - Philosophy of physics (Box 68)
  - Philosophy of physics (Temple University) (Box 68)
  - Photons and material particles, particularly in relation to center of gravity systems (Box 68)
  - Physical properties of sulphur hexafluoride (Box 68)
  - Physicist, Engineer and Inventor (Box 68)
  - Physics (miscellaneous notes), 4 folders (Box 68)
  - Physics and playing of musical instruments, The Staccato (Box 68)
  - Physics as I have known it (Box 68)
  - Piccard stratospheric flight data (Box 69)
  - Piezo-electric phenomena, Notes on (Box 69)
  - Place of science in cultural education (Box 69)
  - Place of science in our civilization, May 3-8, 1943, October 7, 1943 (Box 69)
    Mexico, Swarthmore
  - Planned Universe, October 24, 1958 (Box 69)
  - Poem. Birth of an opal (Box 69)
  - Poincare's treatment (Box 69)
  - Point electron moving with rectilinear velocity (Box 69)
  - Polarization and quantum physics (Box 69)
  - Polarization and quantum theory (Box 69)
  - Positron (Box 69)
  - Postulates of the Bohr theory (Box 69)
  - Potential gradient, Device for measuring from airplanes (Box 69)
  - Potential V at Point P etc. Determination (Box 69)
  - Potentials and field of a point charge (Box 69)
  - Pragmatic approach to elementary principles of wave mechanics (Box 69)
  - Present status of atmospheric electricity. Wentworth-by-the-Sea (Box 69)
  - Presentation of the Franklin Medal to Niels Bohr (Box 69)
  - Pressure of radiation (Box 69)
  - Princeton University. Palmer Physical Lab. Budget, 1925-1926 (Box 69)
  - Principle of relativity (Box 69)
  - Probability of counter-discharge in the case of three counters arranged around a large tank, June 3, 1933 (Box 69)
  - Problem of counter with a hole in wall collecting ions from outside (unfinished) (Box 69)
  - Problem of the accelerometer (Box 69)
  - Problem of the generator (Box 69)
  - Problems (unfinished) (Box 69)
  - Problems in physics. (Box 69)
  - Production of tone in bowed musical instruments (Box 69)
  - Progress of physical sciences (Box 69)
    Pupin Banquet. Toastmaster
  - Prop counters and statistical fluctuations (unfinished) (Box 69)
  - Proportional converter(?) experiments (Box 69)
  - Proportional counter (Box 69)
  - Proposal for ring current around the Earth experiments (Box 69)
  - Protection against radiation in atomic attack (Box 69)
  - Protons at sea level (Box 69)
  - Publications of Swann, from the beginning of his professional career (Box 69)
  - Quantum theory, 4 folders (Box 69-70)
  - Quantum theory, A modified... (unfinished) (Box 70)
  - Questions which have been submitted...by Dr. Leonard Eisenbud (Box 70)
  - Radiation absorption and heat production in reactor (unfinished) (Box 70)
  - Radiation and atomic structure (Box 70)
  - Radiation and the quantum theory (Box 70)
  - Radiation from fine wives at low temperatures, 3 folders (Box 70)
  - Radiation reaction in wave mechanics (Box 70)
  - Radiation theory (Box 70)
  - Radio address, Nov. 18, 1957 (Box 70)
  - Radio talk and cello playing over WFIL, December 6, 1940 (Box 70)
  - Radioactivity (Box 70)
  - Rays to be measured by particle counter (Box 70)
  - Reality in science, May 18, 1940 (Box 70)
    Brown Chapter of Sigma Xi
  - Recent advances in physics (Box 70)
  - Recent advances in physics (Box 70)
  - Red shift, Restricted theory and general theory (Box 70)
  - Reflection of acoustical waves (Box 70)
  - Reflexions (Box 70)
  - Regarding finances (Box 70)
  - Relation of mathematics to physics (Box 70)
  - Relation of pure mathematics to laws for electric fields; etc (Box 70)
  - Relation of the restricted to the general theory of relativity (Box 70)
  - Relation of theory to experiment in physics (Box 70)
  - Relativity (Box 70)
  - Relativity (Box 70)
  - Relativity and electrodynamics (Box 70)
  - Relativity and gravitation (Box 70)
  - Relativity and spectral lines (Box 70)
  - Relativity in reference to the centrifuge experiment (Box 71)
  - Relativity, General theory of (Box 71)
  - Relativity. Lecture (Box 71)
  - Remarks on papers by Condon Kemble, and Slater at Physics Symposium; Franklin Institute, Dec. 9, 1937 (Box 71)
  - Report to the APS, Sept. 15, 1935 (Box 71)
  - Reports of W.F.G. Swann for the months..., January-March 1918 (Box 71)
  - Report of W.F.G. Swann for the months..., May-June 1918 (Box 71)
  - Report of visit to London to receive an honorary fellowship (Box 71)
  - Representation of Radiation resistance on basis of Poynting's theorem (Box 71)
  - Research in industry (Box 71)
  - Research in science. Dedication of Northwestern Techology Institute, June 16, 1942 (Box 71)
  - Researches and problems (unfinished) (Box 71)
  - Researches on magnetized particles, October 2, 1958 (Box 71)
  - Resolving power (Box 71)
  - Retirement as director of the Bartol Foundation (Box 71)
  - Review of Recent Research in Physics, 7 Folders, 1923-1924 (Box 71)
  - Reynolds numbers and associated matters (Box 71)
  - Riddle of the Atom (Box 71)
  - Rockets (Box 71)
  - Role of impedance and allied, concepts re transmission line (Box 71)
  - Role of impedance gen. to include losses in the line (Box 71)
  - Role of logarithms douvature(?) (Box 71)
  - Role of mathematics in physical theories, January 8, 1958 (Box 71)
  - Role of music in our civilization, June 12, 1943 (Box 71)
    Philadelphia Musical Academy, commencement address
  - Role of primary cosmic radiation (Box 71)
  - Role of societies in relation to adult education, Jan. 30, 1942 (Box 71)
    ACLS
  - Rome (N.Y.) Air Development Center (Box 71)
  - Rossi curve (unfinished) (Box 71)
  - Rubber particle problem, March 3, 1946 (Box 71)
    Also letter from "Walter" to Swann
  - Rubber problems Line of thought (Box 71)
  - Satellites (Box 71)
  - Scaling problems in relation to synchrotron (Box 71)
  - Scattering (unfinished) (Box 71)
  - Scheme for submarine detection (Box 72)
  - Schwinger's Princeton Lectures. Swann's notes (Box 72)
  - Science (magazine), Editorial Board Correspondence, A-Z, 25 folders (Box 72)
  - Science and civilization (Box 72)
    Kansas State College, Manhattan, Kansas
  - Science and civilization (Box 72)
    New York Adult Education Committee
  - Science and human happiness (Box 72)
  - Science and practical affairs (Box 72)
  - Science and satellites (Box 73)
  - Science and the performance of music, April 30, 1949 (Box 73)
    American Matthay Association at Franklin Institute
  - Science and the Unknown, November 26, 1956 (Box 73)
    For Arthur Boyd before a group of clergymen, Philadelphia
  - Science and theology (My faith) (Box 73)
  - Scientific comments (Letters) (Box 73)
  - Scientific instruments: Design, methods, where obtainable (Box 73)
  - Scientific memoranda, 6 folders (Box 73)
  - Scientific Memoranda. Dr. Burlew (Box 73)
  - Scientific method (Box 73)
  - Scientist in action (book review, Scientific Monthly) (Box 73)
  - Scope and purpose of physics (Box 73)
  - Second hump as a phenomenon of decay electrons (unfinished) (Box 74)
  - Shear modulus and viscosity, Memorandum (Box 74)
  - Shower production by mesotron in different materials (Box 74)
    Letter to the editor
  - Significance of beauty in music, classic and modern (Box 74)
  - Significance of coordinates in relation to line elements (Box 74)
  - Significance of directional effects in re sign of charge of cosmic ray (Box 74)
  - Significance of modern atomic theories (Box 74)
  - Significance of scientific theories (Box 74)
  - Significance of variation of residual ionization with pressure (Box 74)
  - Solution of (Box 74)
  - Solution of steady state problems, etc (Box 74)
  - Sommerfeld, A.: Production of x-radiation according to wave mechanics (Box 74)
  - South Kensington Board of Education (Box 74)
  - Space current densities, limitation on, etc (Box 74)
  - Space, Time, and Cosmology (Box 74)
  - Specific heats of solids (Box 74)
  - Spectrograph, magnetic momentum (Box 74)
  - Spherical harmonics (Box 74)
  - Staccato (Box 74)
  - Standards and criteria, Dec. 14, 1933 (Box 74)
    Arts Club address. Washington, D.C.
  - Stars and atoms (Box 74)
  - Stars and atoms, January 17, 1955 (Box 74)
  - Statement of wave mechanical theory of conservative dynamical systems (Box 74)
  - Statistics, Quantum Statistics and Thermodynamics (Box 75)
  - Statistical theory and thermodynamics (Box 75)
  - Status of the cosmic ray problem (Box 75)
  - Stoke' theorem (Box 75)
  - Stokes-Planck theory and the Michelson-Morley experiment (Box 75)
  - Stoppage of a Bullet (Box 75)
  - Story of Cp - Cv for any substance (Box 75)
  - Strain gauge measurements (Box 75)
  - Stratosphere Flights (Box 75)
    - Charts from L.T. Briggs, 1935 (Box 75)
    - Correspondence (3 Folders), 1934-35 (Box 75)
    - Data, 1935 (Box 75)
    - Expense Accounts, 1934-35 (Box 75)
    - Memoranda, 1934 (Box 75)
    - Memoranda, 1935 (Box 75)
  - Strength of solids (unfinished) (Box 75)
  - Stress and strain (Box 75)
  - Stromberg's device (Box 75)
  - Submarine correspondence (Agnew, McGrath, Swann), 3 folders (Box 75)
  - Submarine memoranda, 5 folders (Box 75-76)
  - Successive integrations, 6 folders (Box 76)
  - Suggestions for research (Box 76)
  - Suggestions for the exhibit concerned with relativity (Box 76)
  - Survey of progress in physics (Box 76)
  - Swann, W. F. G. Publications (Box 76)
  - System in uniform rectilinear motion (Box 76)
  - Systems considered separately and as a whole (Box 76)
  - Teaching of physics at Haverford, October 21, 1950 (Box 76)
  - Television series (for 13 weeks), December 5., 1954 (Box 76)
  - Temperature arising from viscous flow (Box 76)
  - Temple University. Lectures (Box 76)
  - Tensile strength of crystalline structures (unfinished) (Box 76)
  - Terrestrial magnetism (Encyclopedia Britannica) (Box 76)
  - Theoretical discussion of high energy charged particles, etc (Box 76)
  - Theory of absorption cell (sent to Haust, Franklin Institute), Dec. 17, 1955 (Box 76)
  - Theory of bowed strings (unfinished) (Box 76)
  - Theory of charging effect on insulated body exposed to primary corpuscular radiation, etc (Box 76)
  - Theory of cosmic ray asymmetry (Box 76)
  - Theory of cosmic ray phenomena based on single primary components (Box 76)
  - Theory of differential equations (Lectures by Prof. F. R. Moulton) (Box 76)
  - Theory of quadrant electrometer (unfinished) (Box 76)
  - Theory of relativity, 2 folders (Box 77)
  - Theory of solids with special relation to strength (Box 77)
  - Theory of the single fiber electroscope and a new design of the instrument (Box 77)
  - Thermal conductivity (Box 77)
  - Thermocouple system, Efficiency of, as generator of power (Box 77)
  - Thermocouple. Filrad (Box 77)
  - Thermodynamics (new) (Box 77)
  - Thermodynamics (old) (Box 77)
  - Thermodynamics and statistical mechanics (Box 77)
  - Thermodynamics, Addendum to second law (Box 77)
  - Things of which the universe is made, March 8, 1936 (Box 77)
    Radio address
  - This year of promise in science (Box 77)
    Radio talk, NBC
  - Thomson, J. L. Obituary (Box 77)
    Scientific Monthly
  - Time (Box 77)
  - Time constant for tray of n Counters (Box 77)
  - Training in physics, Dec. 20, 1932 (Box 77)
    American Association of Physics Teachers, Atlantic City, N.J.
  - Transition. Classical to Quantum theory (Box 77)
  - Transposition (Box 77)
  - Transposition in music (A circular scheme with clefs) (Box 77)
  - Trend of thought in modern physics (Box 77)
  - Trend of thought in physics (Box 77)
  - Twentieth Century natural philosophy, June 20, 1928 (Box 77)
  - Two aspects of the quantum theory (Box 77)
  - Types of statistics (Box 77)
  - Unipolar induction. Digest (Box 77)
  - University of Michigan, Report on visit (Box 77)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 3 folders (Box 78)
  - Unsolved problems of cosmical physics (Box 78)
  - Vacuum (Box 78)
    For Encyclopedia Britannica
  - Van de Graaff (Box 78)
    - Generators and associated equipment (Hollingsworth, News) (Box 78)
    - Memorandum. Concerning the program for large generator (Box 78)
    - Memorandum. Fluctuation of; beam (Box 78)
    - Memorandum. Re: committees on large generator (Box 78)
    - Memorandum sent to Hudspeth and Charlie (Box 78)
    - Memorandum. Ionization in a magnetic field (Box 78)
  - Variation of mesotron intensity with altitude, etc (Box 78)
  - Variation of mesotron intensity, etc (Box 78)
  - Variation with altitude and latitude of cosmic radiations etc (Box 78)
  - Variation with altitude and latitude of the vertical component of the cosmic radiation (with P. A. Morris) (Box 78)
  - Varma's experiment, memorandum (Box 78)
  - Vector analysis (Box 78)
  - Vector fields (Box 78)
  - Vectors generalized (Box 78)
  - Velocity of flow of a non-electrically conducting liquid (Box 78)
  - Vibrating string galvanometer (Box 78)
  - Viscosity, as measured by torsional vibrations (Box 78)
  - Viscous liquid flow through a tube (Box 78)
  - Volume of space (Box 78)
  - Wagner Free Institute. Lectures (Box 78)
  - Wave mechanical theory of scattering (Rutherford formula) (Box 78)
  - Wave mechanical theory of scattering with reference to the Rutherford formula. W. F. G. Swann and Cairns. (unfinished) (Box 78)
  - Wave mechanics (Box 78)
  - What are cosmic rays? (Chicago), June 27, 1938 (Box 79)
  - What can a pound of uranium do? (Box 79)
  - What does music mean to a student of natural philosophy? (Box 79)
  - What has become of the aether? (Box 79)
  - What is a cosmic Ray? (Rochester), December 12, 1939 (Box 79)
  - What is left of the atom? (Box 79)
  - What is science? (Box 79)
  - What the heck then is music? (Box 79)
  - What the heck then is music?, Dec. 11, 1944 (Box 79)
    Cosmos Club
  - Where is physics headed? (Box 79)
  - Work of the Bartol Foundation (Box 79)
    Sigma Xi Chapter, Swarthmore
  - Wright field rocket progress (unfinished) (Box 79)
  - Yale University (Box 79)
- Series III. Bound Volumes, ca.1903-1961; 66.0 Volume(s)
  Among the few notebooks that are clearly identified, most appear to contain notes taken by Swann as a student at the Royal College of Science at Brighton. Eight volumes contain laboratory notes kept at the Physical Laboratory, University of Sheffield.
  The series also includes four scrapbooks kept by Swann throughout his career that include newspaper clippings, lecture notices and ephemera relating to his work. One scrapbook is devoted exclusively to his musical interests.
  - "Civil Defense, Where is it?", ca.1950 (Box 79)
  - Course notes, Temple University, 1960-1961; 2 vols., mimeographs (Box 79)
  - Electrodynamics, n.d.; 2 vols., mimeographs (Box 80)
  - Class notes, Brighton and Royal College of Science, ca.1903-1907; 44 vols. (Box 81 - 99, 102 - 104, 107 - 108)
  - Research notebooks, Physical Laboratory, University of Sheffield, ca.1907-ca.1913; 8 vols. (Box 100 - 101)
  - Miscellaneous loose-leaf notebooks, n.d.; 2 vols. (Box 105 - 106)
  - Scrapbook, 1924-1940; 1 vol. (Box 109)
  - Scrapbook, 1945-1962; 1 vol. (Box 110)
  - Musical scrapbook, 1936-1954; 1 vol. (Box 111)
  - Commemorative dinner, 1959; 1 vol. (Box 112)
    Includes letters from invitees and other materials relating to a commemorative dinner held by the Franklin Institute upon Swann's retirement to emeritus status.
- Series IV. Architecture of the Universe, 1933-1935; 1.0 Linear feet
  Typescript copy of Swann's Architecture of the Universe, along with related correspondence, early drafts, notes and reviews.
  - Correspondence, 1934; 2 folders (Box 113)
  - Index and Chapter 1, 2 folders (Box 113)
  - Chapter 2 (Box 113)
  - Chapter 3, 2 folders (Box 113)
  - Chapter 4, 2 folders (Box 113)
  - Chapter 5, 2 folders (Box 113)
  - Chapter 6 (Box 113)
  - Chapter 7 (Box 114)
  - Chapter 8, 2 folders (Box 114)
  - Chapter 9 (Box 114)
  - Chapter 10, 2 folders (Box 114)
  - Chapter 11 (Box 114)
  - Chapter 12, 2 folders (Box 114)
  - Figures (Box 114)
  - Early Notes and Drafts, 4 folders (Box 114)
  - Reviews (Box 114)
- Series V. Images and Certificates, ca.1920s-1962; 1.0 Linear feet
  Photographs, Lantern Slides, glass transparencies, membership certificates, diplomas. In addition to the photographs housed within the Swann Papers, 421 Swann photographs are located in the APS Photograph Collection.
  - Photographs - Portraits, 2 folders (Box 115)
  - Photographs - Portraits and Snapshots, See Also Oversize (Box 115)
  - Photographs - Music (Box 115)
  - Membership Certificates, See Also Oversize (Box 115)
  - Photographs - Glass Transparencies, 6 glass plates (Box 115)
  - Photographs from APS Photograph Collection.
    - Photograph of sketch of W. F. G. Swann, porfile with glasses., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Sketch of Swann, profile.
    - Sketch of W. F. G. Swann, holding cane., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Pencil sketch of Swann, holding cane, water bottle (?) on table top.
      General note
      Possible signature: "Haus [?] 29"
    - Sketch of W. F. G. Swann., n. d.; 1.0 Item(s); Pencil sketch of Swann, wearing hat.
    - "The luncheon in Scott Hall, 15 June 1942.", 1942 June 15; 1.0 Photograph(s); Swann and others seated at table eating.
    - Full length view of W. F. G. Swann, standing outside with gourp of men and women, during a trip to Southampton., 1925 August; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length, group portrait outside, buildings and trees in background.
      Inscription on reverse identifies group as British Association, visiting Southampton.
    - Group of people standing in classroom, "December 13, 1926, The big Party.", [ca. 1929]; 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait of men and women, standing in classroom.
      Note on reverse: "with letter of 19 December, 1926."
    - W. F. G. Swann and five other men, informal group portrait., 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait, Swann standing second row left.
    - Group portrait of W. F. G. Swann and others, standing on steps outside building., 1.0 Photograph(s); Large group of people standing outside on steps, Swann near the front, holding cane.
    - W. F. G. Swann, formal portrait., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Mounted photograph of Swann.